# JOHN JANG

## **Product Designer**

+1 647 553 3499

iscolbe9675@gmail.com

https://www.iohniang.ca/

in/iohniang94

## **SUMMARY**

A Product Designer, graduated fresh from York University in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, actively developing a career in crafting user experience while carrying a year of experience in web development. Coming with a background in Neuroscience, Education, and Software Development, I am actively participating in the process of designing product concepts while considering the development perspective such as the User Interface development. Despite short periods of involvement in the past projects, I have still been successful in delivering the results that meet the expectation of stakeholders. My strengths include strategic designing, initiating projects, and leading communications with internal and external teams. By nature, I am analytical, perceptive, and enjoy problem-solving. Outside of work, I am a runner, dancer, and a potential traveler.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Product Designer Internship The Sakhi

06 / 2024 ~ Present | Remote, Toronto

- · Designed culturally specific shopping experience in the pilot phase
- Conducted regular design critique sessions with Shopify developers to refine features and functionality based on feedback
- Identified 8+ user flow pain points and improved the shopping experience through data-driven adjustments aligned with business goals

# UX/UI Design Apprentice

#### **TeleVU Innovation**

06 / 2022 ~ 08 / 2022 | Remote, Toronto

- Conducted user research with 30 participants gathering insights that informed feature prioritization and usability
- Revamped video call service design, driving a 60% rise in call duration

#### Store Staff

### **Loblaw Companies Ltd**

10 / 2021 ~ Present | Remote, Toronto

- Implemented an electronic navigation map to reduce the time spent on looking for products among Loblaw shoppers by 20%
- Maintained proper stock management and actively participated in sales to keep up the record sale of 25% every quarter

#### VOLUNTEER

#### Product Designer **OperateEase**

09 / 2024 ~ Present | Remote, Toronto

- · Developed a comprehensive design system to standardize UI components and hosted UX Design workshops to align with stakeholders and gather insights from users
- · Led the design of an inventory management system, optimizing room occupancy and supply management, increasing efficiency by 60% from the usability tests
- · Collaborated closely with engineering teams to ensure design feasibility

#### Web Development Apprentice **Tech Fleet Professional Association**

08 / 2023 ~ 09 / 2024 | Remote, Toronto

· Collaborated with UX designers to develop user-friendly applications, ensuring design integrity alongside development teams

# UX/UI Design Apprentice

**Tech Fleet Professional Association** 

04 / 2023 ~ 07 / 2023 | Remote, Toronto

### **EDUCATION**

# **UX** Design

**York University** 

North York, Ontario

#### Web Development Bootcamp

**Dream Coding Academy** September 2022 ~ July 2023

Remote, Toronto

# Psychology & Neuroscience

**University of New Brunswick** September 2013 ~ June 2017

Fredericton, NB

## TOOLS & SKILLS

Figma, Figjam, Miro, Wireframing, Sketching, Typography, Prototyping, Mock-ups, A/B Testing, Usability Testing Waterfall, User-Interface Design, User Research HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, Next.js, React, Vite, MongoDB, Express.js, Axios

#### OTHER LINKS

**My Web Development Portfolio My Github Profile** 

### OTHER INFO

Portfolio password: portfolio